America,
we are at war. Globalists [music] and
leftists threaten the highest levels of
our state and federal governments. Our
[music] state houses, Congress, the
Supreme Court, and even the highest
office of the land has come [music]
under their attack. These dissidents are
laboring to indoctrinate our children,
to corrupt our [music] morals, to divide
our people, and are even working to
eradicate God. But the weapon they
[music] cannot withstand, a power that
can break their forces, is a people that
are united under God and armed with his
truth. Now, [music] join Dr. Steve
Taylor, pastor of Trinity Christian
Church of Suffach, director of Christian
Rights [music] Ministries and president
of the Alliance Legal and the Alliance
Bankruptcy Groups, collectively known as
Alliance Law, for another episode of
Steve Taylor's Last Day's News.
>> Good afternoon, folks. God bless you.
Steve Taylor, Last Day's News. looking
forward to having a great conversation
with you today and also just getting
some more uh information on that
timeline um and some of the details on
that timeline that allow everything to
make sense. Remember that timeline we
talked about the last the end of the
world timeline
uh the uh the 70th week of Daniel.
That's the timeline we're talking about.
Colleen, uh good afternoon. How are you
doing today?
>> Good afternoon. I know it seems like
these weeks are flying by. It's crazy.
>> It really is. We're uh past the midpoint
going towards the uh the home stretch of
the end of this year. And that's kind of
like how I feel for the I'm telling you
uh folks and and Colleen that um every
message that I get prompted to that's in
my spirit is to let people know, hey,
listen, this is not a drill. you know
that uh the Bible talks about the 70th
week of Daniel and um you know that he
tells us things before they come to
pass. But we have to read them. We have
to understand them. We have to
acknowledge them and then we have to you
know James says you know be hearers of
the word not doers only. then do the
things we're supposed to do if we're
that last
segment of that last generation that is
going to see uh Jesus, you know. And so,
uh, I'm telling you, it's it's it's, uh,
I don't know if it's frustrating or if
it's just, um, disturbing, uh, that
people don't, um, you know, there's this
this thing that we see that Jesus tells
people in Matthew 25:es
1-13, the parable of the, uh, the
virgins that the sleeping virgins, all
of them were asleep. And that's clearly
the case that we see going into this
time period. So you can get the word,
you can you can uh show the prophecies,
you can show the geopolitical current
events being satisfied by those
prophetic utterances, yet people still
remain asleep that the veil continues to
be on. Especially, you know, you talk
about Israel, uh, that I have folks that
in my in my in my church, uh, in my in
my Sunday school, in my Bible studies,
that they they witness and that they
sometimes witness to, uh, national Jews.
You know, Jews that, you know, as best
as we can tell, are actually Jewish. You
know, that from a J new Jewish national
standpoint, not just from a
converting over to Judaism. and there's
a veil uh that they don't they do not
you can put the information in front of
them and that they don't get it and
that's because that God says there's a
veil over their eyes until that day that
we see in Zechariah that they wake up
and all Israel is saved in a day is what
the scriptures tell us. So, with that
being said, folks, God bless you. Again,
last days news. We're going to pray.
We're going to jump into this. We're
going to be talking about the temple.
Uh, how people say, "Well, listen. How
can this whole thing happen unless
there's a temple?" Well, uh, there's a
couple options. And, uh, it doesn't have
to be a construction crew and a a bunch
of brick and mortar building something
on the Temple Mount. We we're going to
go over that. Uh, with that being said,
uh, Colin, we're going to jump into
prayer. Then we're going to do a little
bit of Bible reading, and then we're
going to see the last day's news.
happening today uh and uh in today's in
today's events, today's world. And so,
let's pray. Father, we love you and we
thank you and praise you and we going to
trust you with that person that's
listening today that uh Lord that you're
speaking to that you want them to
recognize that the time is short and
eternity is long, very long, and that uh
we want to make sure where we're going
before that time happens. So, we pray
this in Jesus name. Amen.
All right. So, what we're going to be
talking about today, folks, is going to
be
where will he sit? And the first one
we're talking about, um, Colleen, is the
antichrist.
And I'm going to give you there's
basically three positions.
There's basically three positions from
Protestant, evangelical,
um,
premillennial. That means that we're
living here in the premillennial time
period before the thousand years
position. So if you're a a bibleelving
Christian and that you're you're
believing that Jesus is going to come
back at some point and then there's
going to be a thousand-y year reign. The
question is is when's he going to
return? Is it going to be prior to the
seven end of the 70th last seven years
of Daniel? Uh that's what they call a
pre-tribulation rapture. or is it going
to be sometime during that period of
time uh particularly after the 3 and a
half year period particularly I believe
at the sixth year time frame the sixth
seal time frame that's what we call the
prrath position and then some people
believe uh that he comes back in this at
the end of the seventh year at at
Armageddon uh and that's the post-trip
uh version of the story and so but
whatever that is there's going to be a
point in time that we all agree that the
antichrist is going to take the temple.
Uh I use that temple with big air quotes
and say that he's God. We know that that
that's what I like to call the midnight
cry. That's going to be the time period
that everybody that had
um I'm that are still here during that
seven-year period and that they they
hear that uh that statement from this
person inside the uh on the temple
complex. We'll put it that way. They're
going to say, "Oh my goodness, that
means that's the antichrist. Oh my
goodness, that means we're three and a
half years in. Oh my goodness, that
means I was wrong about the
pre-tribulation wrath. Oh my goodness.
That means that uh all hell is literally
going to break loose uh during that
period of time going forward. And so
with that being said that for
uh all three camps,
the question becomes
where is he going to sit? Where is he
going to be? And so that's what's going
to happen because and we'll get to get
into that. There's three basic options.
And so let's jump into that. So for
decades, the standard answer is
option one. There's going to be a
rebuilt Jewish temple, a third temple, a
big construction project. And for
decades, the standard objection has been
impossible. The world won't allow it.
The Muslims uh won't allow it. There's
no time. And honestly, the objections
that say that basically that we don't
have a temple on the temple mount and
it's real hard to get one up there has
kept a lot of people from taking the
seven 70th week seriously at all. But
today we're going to that's answer
that's that's that's basically we're
already one-third of the the issues
down. Colleen one is and you've heard
that one too, right? That there's going
to be a temple built, right? You got a a
u the temple institute say we're going
to build a temple on this thing. We got
to put all the stuff in it. We're going
to have the the priest and the
sacrifices and all the implements of
this newly rebuilt temple uh in
Jerusalem and uh we're going to put it
there soon. And we've heard that. We've
grown up with that. And we've always
wondered, well, how is they going to put
a big temple, you know, like e even the
smaller Solomon's or or the the pre
Solomon the you had the Solomon temple
and and then you had the the um uh the
the the second temple. How are we going
to get a big temple on the Temple Mount
with the Dome of the Rock on there,
right? Uh how you know that? That's an
issue, isn't it, Colleen?
Right. It's logistics.
>> It's it's logistics. You got you got a a
mosque on there that they claim is I
think the third most important site on
their their uh calendar uh their
religious calendar and it's sitting
there and it's where the the the temple
should be. And so the people say, "Well,
you know, there's going to be a lot of
stuff happen and that um you know, we're
not there yet. So, you know, let's move
on. Nothing to see here. There's so much
to go. you know, once we see the, you
know, the back in the Iraqi war days
that, you know, the Scud missile take
out that thing and people start to try
to build. Well, yeah, then maybe we are
close. Or, you know, maybe that there's
a deal made with Trump and the
Jordanians and everybody involved that
uh will allow them to, I guess, move or
put a temple on the Temple Mount like
right near the I mean, there's been all
kinds of solutions. People said, "Well,
maybe the temple's supposed to go in
David's uh city, which is not even the
place where it's supposed to be at."
It's, you know, that the uh So, but
bottom line is is the Jewish people know
that the Temple Mount is where the
temple goes, and that there's a big old
thing on top of it called the Dumb of
the Rock uh that basically prevents the
temple from being built where it's
supposed to be built. We're going to get
to what is where the the pavement stone
is or the place where uh the ark was
later, but trust me, based upon the
archaeology and the um the biblical uh
study that experts have done, it does
appear to be under the Dome of the Rock,
the pavement stone, the place where um
it all happened uh where the ark used to
be uh is carved out in the the the stone
there. So, it's level uh on the temple
mount now and the Dome of the Rock is on
top of it. So, argument one can't
happen. You're pushing things too quick.
It'll take a long time to get rid of the
dome and then build a new temple on it.
Go about your business. Nothing to see
here. That's option one. But there's two
answers that say, "Hey, listen. That's
not correct. If we're in the 70th week,
it could happen any time. It could
happen very, very quickly." And so um
and so we're going to look at both those
those uh possibilities today. The first
one comes from Nelson Walters. Again,
we've spoken about Nelson uh many times
and you can go to his YouTube channel
channel just put Nelson Walters and
you'll come up with it. And he had two
videos that came up very recently that
basically describes
uh one option. It's not the option I
actually think is going to happen, but
reasonable minds would disagree. And
this certainly there's some elements to
it that I agree with. But the second one
is the one I believe is going to be the
the case, which is the third option.
Remember the construction project, the
10-year time frame, whatever you want to
call it. That's the most recent one that
has been going on for years and years
and years. The second one we're going to
talk about Nelson's, and I'll give you
the spoiler alert. It's about a mobile
temple uh like a tabernacle being
wheeled up and then uh it not being too
important to begin with because the the
bottom line is is that you can do an
altar which is where they actually do
the sacrifices. We'll talk about that uh
with that second thing. The third one's
going to be mine and it's again there's
people that have discussed portions of
it but never I haven't seen one that
puts it all together as the likely and
actual option uh which is going to be I
can tell you what it's going to be ahead
of time. It's about the Dome of the Rock
uh housing going to be that the Dome of
the Rock can stay that the the temple
never says it can't be um uh that that
it that it can't be that that that the
Dome of the Rock uh doesn't
leave the leave the Dome of the Rock.
He's going to go inside the Dome of the
Rock. That satisfies scripture and
nothing else is necessary. So, let's go
through the necessary stuff that have to
happen according to scripture so that
any one of these three propositions,
let's just bury down into it. Colleen,
how can people call in and discuss what
their thoughts are on this subject?
>> Phone lines are 757-488-5299
757-488-5299.
Yeah, we're here till 1:30, so call in.
So, no matter what your position is,
there's three non-negotiables, what
scripture requires, and we're going to
go over those just so you know what the
parameters are that we have to fit
whatever theory we've got about where
the antichrist is going to sit or stand
uh before as just parameters that it has
to fit into. So, the first one, Colleen,
is going to be from the book of Daniel,
chapter 9, verse 27. Can you read that
one?
>> Daniel 9. Mhm.
>> Verse 27.
>> Yep.
>> Is
and he shall confirm the covenant with
many of one week for for one week. And
in the midst of the week, he shall cause
the sacrifice and the oblation to cease
and for the over
>> That's good. That's good. Uh the the key
words there uh that you read, Colleen,
the things I want to focus on today is
that he shall cause the sacrifices and
oblations to cease.
So the issue is, Colleen, I'm just going
to speak to you like we're speaking to
the whole crowd. You can't st stop, but
you never started. If the antichrist,
you've heard this before, uh causes the
daily sacrifice to cease at the
midpoint, then the daily sacrifice must
be running prior to that. Correct.
That's non-negotiable. Does that make
sense?
>> That makes sense. Yes. So if we're
believing that October 2024, which is
the date that I've set out in my
dissertation and have provided a number
of different uh amount of evidence
saying that could be the date if October
24, Rashashana 2024, uh fees of trumpets
2024, uh Yamur, all the same words for
the same date, the beginning of the the
head of the year, the beginning of the
70th week, the last seven years started
on on approximately October 2nd or 3rd,
uh two days because it's the date that
no one knows the date of, right? It's
the feast that no one knows the date of.
Two days, sliver of moon, that thing. If
that stopped October 24th, then the
midpoint's going to happen um uh
Passover 28, about April 2028, three and
a half years, less than two years away.
Uh that's when all this happens. So
sometime in the next year and a half
between now and Passover 2028,
sacrifices would have to start in order
for them to stop on that date.
Requirement two, um, read Matthew 24:15.
>> All right. Matthew 24:15
is, "When ye therefore shall see the
abomination of desolation spoken of by
Daniel the prophet, stand in the holy
place. Who so readeth, let him
understand."
>> Okay. So, it says, "When you therefore
shall see the abomination of desolation
spoken by Daniel the prophet, stand in
the rebuilt temple." Is that what it
says?
>> Mine says holy place.
>> Ah, so it doesn't say stand in the
temple. It says stand in the holy place.
Mark those words. Jesus did not say
stand in the rebuilt temple. He said the
holy place in the Greek topos hagios a
place a location and he attached to
command. Whoso readeth let him
understand. He expects us to read
carefully.
Daniel tells us that in the end times
when the seals are opened, people's
understanding will increase and so will
ours because we're those folks. We're
going to get back to that. But again,
he's going to stand in the holy place.
We're going to go back over that. Um, so
the requirement three, uh, read 2
Thessalonians 2:4.
All right. 2 Thessalonians 2:4. who
opposeth and exalteth himself above all
that is called God or that is worshiped
so that he as God siteth in the temple
of God showing himself that he is God.
>> Okay? And so this is where they get the
temple language from his God siteth in
the temple. There you go Mr. Taylor uh
Dr. Steve that there's a temple and we
need to rebuild it. Well, we're gonna
hold on to that verse and the exact word
Paul chose as temple is going to become
the crux of this whole
of my whole uh presentation of my whole
position. Now, couple things just so we
can get rid of those so that we don't
spend a lot of time because we only have
about a half an hour to get the rest of
this thing done. that whatever the
temple is, whatever the temple is not,
it is not Ezekiel 40-48.
That describes a glorious stone temple
uh of very different dimensions than we
see anywhere else in the prior temples
being built. Uh and it's the millennial
temple. There's lots and lots of proofs
that it is not the and you'll just have
to do a Google search or go to your AI
or whatever you want to do. That is not
the temple we're talking about. That is
not the place where the antichrist is
going to take a seat in. That is the
thousand year the temple that's built at
beginning of the thousand years that
that Jesus will rule and reign in and
that we get to reign with him. Uh it's
built after the Lord returns. That's the
Ezekiel temple. That's the millennial
temple. It is not the temple that we're
talking about. We could spend some more
time discussing it, but uh we're going
to leave that for that today just
because we don't want to rabbit chase
too far. Another one that we don't want
to rabbit chase too far is the temple is
is the believer's heart. We've heard
that, right? That you've heard that um
that um that um
2 Thessalonians chapter 2, let's pull
that up real quick. Just read it because
you'll see it right there. 2
Thessalonians
2.
>> [sighs]
>> Um, oh, hold on. We're going to read
that. But that that um we just read
that, I think. Um,
hold on one second.
the verse I was actually looking for uh
is going to be
um
make sure I got it. Um 1 Corinthians
6:19-20. Do you not know that your
bodies are temples of the Holy Spirit
who is in you whom you have received
from God? You are not your own. You are
bought at a price. Therefore, honor God
with your body. So people say, well, see
Mr. Taylor, Dr. Steve, your bodies are
the temple, right? So that um that's
going to be the temple that's going to
be rebuilt. It's in fact been rebuilt.
The problem with that is in 2
Thessalonians 2:4, God siteth in the
temple of God. He can't sit on your
heart, right? He can't stand on your
heart. So that al although it is correct
that we have become the nails, we're
going to go over that. the place of
God's dwelling. There is going to be a
physical place that God is going to sit
and that is going to be the
whatever that we hear is going to be
where the man the the the man of sin,
the antichrist is going to sit or stand
in. And we know it's a real event
because
um lots of lots of reasons, but um I
want you to go back and think of uh
Ecclesiastes. Um what is that verse? Uh
Ecclesiastes 1:9. I'll just read it to
you. The thing which has been,
the thing that hath been, it is that
which shall be, and that which is done
is that which shall be done, and there
is no new thing under the sun. So the
the answer is is that um that relates to
the fact that the whole thing that we're
talking about about a very bad person
sitting in the temple uh and um uh
causing the issue and declaring the the
prideful act of him being as God has
happened before in 167 BC Antiocus
Epiphanies
a Greek king who adopted the title which
means God manifest
went into marched into Jerusalem halted
the daily sacrifices just like we talked
about erected a Zeus idol in this in the
temple and offered swine on the altar of
God.
Um Daniel centuries before
said, "They shall pollute the sanctuary
of strength and shall take away the
daily sacrifice, and they shall place
the abomination
that maketh desolate."
All that again, 167 was when they did
that. Hundreds of years before that,
Daniel said they're going to do that.
And then in the first century when Jesus
was uh in his earthly ministry,
uh Jesus said, think of Daniel when he
was talking to the believers in chapter
24, the Olivet discourse, talking about
the end times. Remember that the the
disciples said to him, "When will all
these things happen? You know, the
destruction of the temple, uh the the uh
the when Jesus is going to return, the
end of the age, when's all going to
happen?" Uh and Jesus gives us this this
this sit down with the the disciples and
tells them um that he says consider
Daniel. So he was saying that Daniel's
got the answer. Daniel. So even though
Daniel's words came true in 167 BC with
Antiochus Epiphanies, Jesus says when
he's being responded to when he's when
he's he's he's when he's replying to the
disciples when this is going to happen,
the end of the age, he says, "Think
about Daniel because that's when it's
going to happen." And so that the
Antiochus Epiphanies
thing that that he did was a foreshadow
or a preview of what's going to happen
at the end time. A nearfar sort of
prophecy. It's going to happen once, but
the complete fulfillment is going to
happen in response to the disciples
questions in the end of the age is going
to happen again. They'll pollute the
sanctuary of strength and shall take
away the daily sacrifice and they shall
place the abomination that makes
desolate.
And um so that was history by the time
Jesus spoke about it. So we're looking
for those very things to happen again
at the three and a half year mark.
Daily sacrifices being ended just like
Daniel spoke about. um some sort of
abomination's going to happen in that
place where he sits or stands. Uh and
that that um uh that's going to happen
again. And so position one we talked
about uh it's going to happen when it
happens. Construction project don't know
how it's going to happen. People aren't
in agreement with it. Don't worry about
it. It's not going to happen anytime
soon. Position two,
we look at Nelson Waters position and he
talks about the mobile temple and the
Ezra president. So this is his position.
Remember you can go to YouTube and find
his information there and then you can
watch the 20-minute video. There's a
couple of them just came out. So first
this is about uh the hardware and the
blueprint. The hardware is all the stuff
the Temple Institute's making. you know,
the the uh a modular altar built from
Dead Sea stones, untouched by metal
tools, all prepared per Exodus 20:25,
ready to uh get assembled. They're
sitting in a warehouse designed.
Remember, this altar is separate from
the, you know, the bron the bronze altar
was outside the holy of holies and out
and outside the holy place as well. So
it was out in the courtyard where they
did the sacrifices. And all that stuff
according to the exact precision
required by scripture is designed to be
trucked up to the temple mount and set
up in hours. And so no temple required
to operate an altar. uh ritual purity.
Uh they either have it uh because that
they they
in the Kuman um uh in the in the in the
Kuman clay tablets, you know, the uh the
Essenes um
hid all these different, you know,
scriptures. There was one that was found
that was like a treasure map. I think it
was made of bronze if I'm not mistaken.
uh and that that one pointed to all
these different sort of places that were
hidden treasures. Some people think that
the the red heer um ashes were hidden
different places pursuant to that very
map and and that they're available today
and they found some you don't need a
whole lot to purify this stuff. You
know, you just need a you just need a
little uh cache of of red heer uh ashes
to make everything pure. Additionally,
back last July, they said at first that
it was a uh a practice run for the
heers. They did it in Shiloh and that
they did you hear about that uh uh
Colleen that they they sacrificed a red
heer that came from Texas. There's like
five of them that got together and as
the time frame ran out, they sacrificed
a red heer in Shiloh. Did you hear about
that?
>> I don't remember hearing about that. No.
Well, they did it and that uh they said
that it was a uh it was just like a
practice run, but the the requirements
that the rabbis have in, you know,
Jewish rabbitical
um tradition says that the the red heer
has to be a perfect red heer. I think
it's less than one year old. Uh and that
the uh with zero defects, no white hairs
or one or two white hairs or something.
uh and that that they have to sacrifice
it while looking at the
temple complex through the Easter gates
they say and so that it has to be on the
Mount of Olives and that sacrifice would
then be valid. However,
that the temple used to be in Shiloh.
And so the the thought is that they did
the sacrifice while in view of the
temple. Uh and they did it with all the
ritual requirements necessary. And that
that very well could have been not just
a practice run, but an actual run. and
that they have the ashes from that even
out to purify the the vessels and the
implements and the the altar and the
priest and everybody else. So, um the so
as far as the hardware, they got
everything they need. They have
everything they need just waiting to
pull the trigger. They even have the the
priest uh you know genetically verified
descendants of Levi, you know, the
priest class uh and the line of Aaron,
high priest included. And the family
name Cohen has been carrying the lineage
in plain sight for 2,000 years. I don't
know if you've heard that, but I'm sure
you've heard about the Temple Institute
calling.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> So, they say they got everything ready
to go. It doesn't take any additional
work. They're all ready to go. just
waiting to the do it to do it and and
that the um so it's that's all prepared
and they even have um they even know
where the ark is. They say the Temple
Institute representative when asked
point blank uh whether Israel knows
where the ark is, he said the the the
answer was those that need to know where
it is know where it is.
And that the reason that they haven't
turned it over yet is because that the
thought is again just the the
geopolitical sort of things is that
Jordan actually
uh has territorial rights given to them
in whatever year that was. I guess it
was 67 uh to to claim any kind of
artifact that is uncovered
uh uh on the mount. And they don't want
Jordan to have the ark obviously. So,
they're just not going to say it until
it's time to say it, but they know where
it's at. They got all the stuff. They
got even the art. Uh, and that, uh,
they're ready to go. That's the
hardware. Now, the blueprint. They got
the stuff. Remember, option two is
we got to got to have a new temple,
right? Because the old temple, uh, we
got to have a temple for all the three
requirements. You know, the sacrifices
to stop, the man to sit in the temple.
Um, you know, that kind of thing. So the
blueprint, how are they going to do
this? And this is what Nelson says. He
says, "Listen, uh, go to Ezra chapter 3,
year about 537. Cyrus the Great has
decreed the return of the Israelites
from at that point Persia to, uh,
Israel." And they he made a decree that
many people see as uh very similar to
what uh Trump did in a couple years back
when he declared that uh Jerusalem was
the the capital city of Israel and he
sent the people back. Cyrus the Great uh
sent the people back to
start the sacrifices uh and that all
this was confirmed in what's called the
Cyrus cylinder in the British Museum. uh
and that uh Isaiah named Cyrus if you
remember uh as as God's shepherd perform
all that his pleasure was to accomplish
even saying to Jerusalem thou shalt be
built and to thy temple the foundation
shall be laid and that's what happened
and so God raised a pagan emperor by the
name of Cyrus specifically to uh get the
the initial thing done so um so they did
it they went down there And guess what
they did? They built the walls and the
temples. No, what they did in Ezra 3:1
says, "The people gathered themselves
together as one man to Jerusalem in the
seventh month." And then verse 2 and
three, it says, "They built the altar.
They didn't build the temple. They
didn't um they you know the the
compound. They built the altar and they
set it on its original basis. They say
that because for the fear was upon them
because the people of those countries so
that they were fearful of everybody
going to attack them and they said the
best solution to this is get the
sacrifice moving. Fear didn't stop the
offerings. They started them. And so
they were surrounded by hostile peoples
just like they are today. They ran to
the altar, not away from it. That's what
they're going to do in the end times. I
believe that the first thing they're
going to do is they're going to start
sacrifice. That's what the scripture
tells us. That's what the scripture
requires. That's what they did before
and that's what's going to happen. And
the other thing they tell us exactly
precisely when that's going to happen in
Ezra 3:6, uh, can you read Ezra 36?
>> Ezra 3:6.
From the first day of the seventh month
began they to offer burnt offerings unto
the Lord, but the foundation of the
temple of the Lord was not yet laid.
>> Remember the Ecclesiastes, that's what
has happened. It's going to happen
again. Same thing's going to happen this
time. They're going to get there and
again the first day of the seventh month
is a very important date as well. It's
called Tish 1. That is Rashashana. That
is feast of trumpets. That is Yamura.
That is going to be the date I believe
and Nelson believes the sacrifices are
going to start. There's going to be a
Rashashana. I'm guessing if it's going
to be a year and a half from now,
probably this uh October
or the very latest next October that
you're going to see sacrifices starting
in Jerusalem. You're going to have
sacrifices starting. You're not going to
have a foundation of the the the temple
built. Uh you're not going to have
walls, no building just like in the days
of Ezra. That is the biblical president.
What's happened before is going to
happen again according to Ecclesiastes.
Sacrifice and restart with an altar and
consecrated peace from the temple
institute. Period. And the note that the
the date that it happens is going to be
the same date. It's going to be the
Rashashana, [clears throat] the feast of
trumpets. Uh the day that no one knows
the day or the hour. Uh you know, the
only feast that begins on the new moon.
Uh and
that's what's going to happen according
to Nelson of which I think very possibly
could happen. So I agree with him. So um
Nelson takes one more step. He says,
"Where's it going to happen at?" Right?
Uh what about the holy place? You know,
what about the temple? Doesn't that
require some sort of structure?
Somebody's got to sit down or stand in
this thing uh called the temple or the
holy place. And he says, "Yeah, it's
going to happen. But don't worry, we
don't need to build a build structure.
They didn't do that in the past. We
won't need to do in the future." Um the
uh they could have, he says, a temporary
one. So, let's take a look at Ezra 3:7.
That's the verse right after the last
one. You did 3:7 Ezra.
>> They gave money also unto the masons and
to the carpenters and meat and drink and
oil unto them of Zidon and to them of Ty
to bring cedar trees from Lebanon to the
sea of Japa according to the grant that
they had of Cyrus, king of Persia.
>> Okay? And so what they did was they
started doing the altars and it took
what 16 years to build the darn thing.
So that what it said 16 years before the
stone temple went up, they were doing
sacrifices.
So um
where where was the temple at? What were
they doing? Go to Hagi
chapter 1 verse 8.
>> You said Hagi.
>> Hagi
18. And then
23.
>> Hagi 1 verse8.
go up to the mountain and bring wood and
build the house and I will take pleasure
in it and I will be glorified sayaeth
the Lord.
>> So that's referring to the same thing
Ezra was talking about. He says start 16
years going to build it. Then go to Hagi
23.
>> That verse says, "Who is left among you
that saw this house in her first glory?
And how do you see it now? Is it not in
your eyes in comparison of it as
nothing?"
So they built this structure and again
I'm not sure exactly when it was Haggi
22:3 but it started in Hagi 18 which is
the same verse that we talk about in
Ezra 3:7. They started building using
all these cedars and they looked at and
they said you know that doesn't look
like Solomon's temple. I mean that
doesn't look like uh what we used to
have here. You know, we used to have a
grand super place and some people cried
and some people rejoiced because there
had been a foundation that would was put
there and that it was starting to look
like, you know, something to speak of.
Some people loved it, some people didn't
love it too much. But the bottom line is
it wasn't much compared to the old
temple. Then in Amos 9:11, it tells us
something else. Can you read Amos 9:1?
Amos, let's see.
>> Amos 9. You said Amos 9 verse
>> verse 11.
>> Let's see. That says, "In that day will
I raise up the tabernacle of David that
has fallen and close up the breaches
thereof, and I will raise up his ruins,
and I will build it as in the days of
old."
So what God tells tells us is that the
the the tabernacle of David that was a
tabernacle that was a tent that was a
booth. He says he's going to raise up
that which has been fallen. And so David
pitched a tent for the ark in Jerusalem.
So what Nelson says is expect a mobile
altar and a tent sanctuary deployed in
the hours the moment political
permission comes. So that's the whole
story. He says that basically that
they're going to have all the stuff
ready that just like back in the day
that they're going to start the altars
and then when that time comes at the
three and a half year mark here it comes
the the mobile um the mobile tabernacle
that the the tent uh and that's going to
be how it's going to work. And so that's
their position. Now in the last 15
minutes or so let me tell you what I
think is going to happen. And it's not
completely different from what Nelson
says. It's a whole bunch different than
what the, you know, what we've been
taught up and through now. But here's my
position in one sentence. The 70th week
doesn't require anyone to build
anything. Not a temple, not even a
tabernacle. Because the holy place
already exists. God fixed it forever.
Archaeology has located it and it is
standing right now beneath the Dome of
the Rock. That's my answer.
Now, have you heard that before,
Colleen?
I'm not sure I have. No,
>> other than for me [laughter]
>> just now. Yeah.
>> So, that's my position. And I've
searched the internet. I've searched the
resources. There's people that say
something about that, but not exactly
like that. There's people that we're
going to talk about even as I go through
the reasons that I believe this is going
to uh be the case that agree with
portions, but they haven't put it all
together. So, let me build it in four
steps. First, the vocabulary. When we go
back to Paul in the New Testament, he
has two different words for the temple.
And the difference is everything.
One word for the temple is hyeron. H i r
o n heron. Maybe it means the whole
temple complex. It mean the courts, the
porticos, the buildings, the entire
compound. the structure that we
associate with the temple, you know, the
thing with the wall and the the the holy
of holies and the the the holy place and
the holy of holies inside of it with the
altar outside of the whole big thing.
That's the hyon. Um Jesus drove money
changers and that happened in the high
in the complex in the out courts. Now
naos
the other Greek word means the sanctuary
itself the inner house the holy of
holies the actual dwelling spot of God.
When Jesus says destroy this temple and
in three days I will raise it up
speaking of his body he said naos he
didn't say hieron. Now when Paul wrote
that the man sitth in the temple of God,
he chose Naos as well,
not the campus, not the the whole the
dwelling space. He was talking about the
place where God chose to set his name.
And in Jesus 24:15, the topos heios
means the holy place. That's the other
word. It means a location. It doesn't
mean a temple. And so we go back to
Daniel 9:27 and it says, "For the
overspreading of abominations he shall
make desolate uh in the Hebrew, behind
the overspreading is a kaf, a wing, an
edge or an extremity." So it says on the
wings of the temple, some of your
scripture will say uh or the wings or an
edge of the extremity.
But there's no commandment anywhere in
the New Testament that anybody's going
to build anything. No description of
construction, no requirement of a
completed sanctuary.
And when you look at it like I do from a
with a lawyer point of view, sac it
means I've looked at the contracts. You
got to read the contracts. Look for ex,
you know, exceptions and carveouts. The
text requires sacrifices that can be
stopped and a location that can be
defiled. That's it. Nowhere does it
require a building program. Nowhere does
it require a a temple complex.
Step one. So that's what the Bible says.
The Bible says that it's a place uh and
uh it there's sacrifices that got to be
stopped. So step two, where does
holiness come from? What does that mean?
Holiness description is never
manufactured from below. It's always
declared from above. So when we go to
Exodus
3 verse 5, go ahead and read Exodus 3:5,
Colleen.
Okay. Exodus 3:5.
And he said, "Draw not nigh thither. Put
off thy shoes from off thy feet. For the
place whereon thou standest is holy
ground."
>> So um holiness is because God declared
that place was holy. No building, no
altar, no roof. God spake, dirt became
holy. Right? That's holy ground. Same
thing when the uh the angel of the Lord
uh comes up to Joshua and says, "Take
your feet off. This is holy ground." God
has declared and I believe that was a
christophony, a pre-incarnation
uh of Jesus appearing, a theophony of
God. Uh and he declared that place where
Jo Joshua was as holy ground. And so um
Jesus taught the Pharisees the same
thing in Matthew 23. He says, "Whether
is greater the gold or the temple that
sacrifice the gold, the gift of the
altar that sanctifyth the gift." And so
he says what he basically said is the
sanctity holiness flows down from God's
designation into wherever it's at. So
whatever God declares holy remains holy.
So did God designate a spot? He did.
Take a look at 2 Chronicles 7:16.
>> 2 Chronicles.
>> Yep.
Seven.
>> 16. Yep.
>> Seven. Okay. And I got to turn fast.
Let's see. [laughter]
>> Sword, right?
>> 716.
Good thing I remembered all this stuff
from when I was a kid. [laughter]
>> That's right.
>> For now have I chosen and sanctified
this house that my name may be there
forever and mine eyes and mine heart
shall be there perpetually. So that says
that that God has chosen a place
sanctified, made holy, his house, that
his name may be there until they put the
Dome of the Rock there.
It doesn't say that. He says that until
I'm going put my name there until
a construction project rebuilds a temple
that I can put my name there. He didn't
say that. He said that my name may be
there forever and my eyes and my heart
shall be there perpetually. Perpetually.
Psalm 132 says in Zion, this is my rest
forever. Here will I dwell. Forever
means forever. It means perpetual means
until it goes on forever. The place he's
talking about there, folks, is Mount
Mariah where Abraham raised the knife
over Isaac. where the destroying angel
halted the destruction at Oman's
threshing floor. God attached his name
to that ground in perpetuity.
And here's the question that decides
everything. Does any structure built by
human hands, Roman, Byzantine, or
Islamic, have the authority to revoke
what God has decided? Of course not.
Nebuch Nebuchadnezzar burned Solomon's t
temple to an ash. And Daniel still
opened his window and prayed to
Jerusalem three times a day. Why?
Because the place was holy. It didn't
stop being holy just because
Nebuchadnezzar burned it down. And it
doesn't stop becoming holy because Islam
has built a dome of the rock on it.
And so the returning exiles in Daniel
day set the altar upon his bases, the
original footings, the original spot.
It's a spot in a place that God has
declared holy and that his name will be
there forever. That's where the temple
has to be at. Wherever that place is at,
wherever Mariah's uh Mount Mariah where
Abraham raised the nice, that's the
place. That's the the place where the
the cross was. That's the place where uh
the sacrifice was. Uh that's the place
where uh Isaac was going to be
sacrificed. Same place, same story, same
holiness. God has placed his holiness in
that place forever.
And if you want to prove that God's
holiness outranks any pagan structure,
remember what happened in the
Philistines when the remember this when
the Philistines captured the ark and put
it into the pagan temple of Deaeon. You
remember what happened there,
Colleen?
>> I'm trying to remember.
>> Remember they took the ark. They, you
know, they they they basically got the
ark. They say, "Oh, boy. We got the ark.
let's put it up in in our temple because
um because we're going to get blessed by
it or we're gonna actually we're going
to defile it because you know that it's
going to be in our pagan temple. And so
um what happened what happened to the
the pagan god um Deeon uh and what
happened to the to the ark? Did did
Deeon's temple corrupt the ark? No. We
could read 1st Samuel 5 and uh but let's
just get the short story. They stick
this ark in this
blasphemic Deeon temple and um they
propped their god and that and then what
happened the next morning Deeon was on
his face before the ark. Remember that
he got knocked down.
>> Okay,
>> God didn't want to share his his
presence with with Deeon.
>> So they the the The Philistines got
their god back up on, you know, they
they propped him back up and, you know,
glued stuff back together and then they
came back the next morning and next time
Deeon was on the ground. This time his
head and his hands broken off on the
threshold. Remember that
>> a little bit now? I do.
>> Yeah. And so that the bottom line is the
holiness ran one direction and it wasn't
from the building uh to the ark. A pagan
roof over a holy thing does not profane
the holy thing. It puts the pagan roof
on notice that that get ready that
something's going to happen. Keep that
picture in mind when somebody tells you
this Dome of the Rock, this Muslim
shrine can never stand over the holy
place of God. It can stand. It can't and
it can't revoke God's holiness in that
place. That's the second thing. Third,
we know exactly where the spot is that
it needs to be at. uh a gentleman named
Lean Ritmire uh is a archaeologist and
is extremely credible uh and that he's
an architect uh and of the official
Temple Mount excavations and earned a
doctorate on the architectural
development of the mount itself. If
you're a scholar anywhere in the world,
you listen to Lean Ritmeer because he
knows what he's talking about. I got the
book and what it says is that he
nutshell is the pavement stone. The
place where uh Isaac uh was to be
sacrificed. The place where uh where uh
the
the sacrifice of Jesus uh would where
where the um sacrifice of Jesus where
the ark of the covenant actually sat is
under the dome of the rock. It's in
there's a um a space exactly 1 and 1/2
cubits by 2 and a half straight out of
Exodus 25:10
that they've cut a section that is the
same size as what the ark would have to
be to give it a level place for the ark
to sit and that's the place crusaders
when they u uh took over the dome laid a
marble floor over that rock
but that so when they took took that
off. They found this rectangular imp
placement in a floor uh that was still
there.
So Jewish tradition has always called
that rock the even shitaya, the
foundation stone, the pavement stone
that the ark rested on. That's the
historical truth of it. It is under the
dome. It is exactly where God put it.
Uh, the floor of the Holy Holies is in
plain sight under the Muslim dome right
now. Rip Meyers identified it. Not
everybody agrees. That's just because
they don't they haven't done the
research.
But, um, that's the answer. So, again,
there's more proof that we could set.
We're down to five minutes, so I can't
go more on it, but the bottom line is
the word Naos is the sanctuary. It's a
holy place. It is not the temple
uh you know the temple complex and that
is what
uh and so let me show you how it works
out. What's going to happen in my point
of view likely is the antichrist is
going to walk into a Muslim antichrist
is going to walk into a Muslim uh dome
of the rock and he's going to go to the
place where the pavement stone is which
is the holy place, the Naos.
The Bible calls that the temple. He's
going to go to that place and he's
either going to sit on um a fake ark of
the covenant or possibly even a real arc
of the covenant. People say, "Well, how
can that be? Because then he'll get
killed." Well, God can do whatever he
wants, and if he wants to preserve him,
you know, you've seen that one uh show,
God is dead, I think it is, something
like that. And remember that professor
uh that they said, "Listen, I'm going to
blaspheme God basically. I'm going say
he's a worthless loser, and I dare him
to strike me down dead." You remember
that that thing, Colleen? Something like
that?
>> I'm not sure what you were talking
about.
>> There was a movie, I think it was called
God is Dead. And there was this
professor that was trying to beat up all
the kids as far as their faith. And so
he shows up in the first day of class
and he starts picking on this one kid
that's Christian. And he says, you
remember that?
>> I think so. Yeah. Is that the God's Not
Dead series or whatever?
>> Yeah. He says, "God is dead and he
nothing he can do about it. I'm going to
call him a loser and a whatever he
called him and I dare him to to strike
me dead." And he didn't strike him dead.
But that doesn't mean that he couldn't
have. What it meant was that that he
didn't. And the same thing could happen
with the temple mount. They could
actually find the actual ark, put it
right in the actual place, and that God
could choose not to kill that person
despite the fact that that he should
die. Uh or it could be a fake ark and he
could sit on a fake ark that basically
then not die for that reason. I don't
know exactly that dimension of it, but
that my position is is that that he is
going to enter. You don't need a
physical building. You've already got
one there. And you don't need uh a holy
place. You've already got one there. All
you need is the Antichrist to walk in,
declare that he's God in that place,
whether on a you know, a a chair or a
arc or I don't know how God's going to
do it, but you don't need the the
temple. And what's interesting is my
position and Nelson's positions don't
vary very much really. Uh both say that
um that um political
permission is going to be the trigger.
How's that going to happen? Well, in
Ezra's day, Cyrus gave them the
permission to build. Who could that be
in the future? Well, Cyrus is actually
been compared to Trump. If Trump gets
involved and he wants to give some
permission, take it away from the Jordan
and give permission to do something like
pray and do sacrifices, he very well may
be able to do it. That could be option
one. Political permission, whether it's
a mobile or a don't need a a mobile and
just go into the thing has to happen.
The the um the Nelson says a temporary
sanctuary has to be built. I say no new
structure has to be built at all. It's
already ready to go. The nails of God is
a spot where God declared holy forever
and it already exists. And so that
um why do I put more weight on my
position? Because the precision of the
language Paul Naos and Jesus topos
hakios point to a location not a
building. Uh Nelson's bish position says
we got to have a structure. Doesn't say
that anywhere in the the building.
there's no construction project, no
temple ever being discussed at all in
the entire New Testament. And that um
there's a political reality. Uh think
like a negotiator for me. Ex erecting a
Jewish tabernacle on the Temple Mount
would be very very provocative. This
requires no provocation at all. All they
have to do is a Muslim Antichrist walk
into a Muslim dome and do what he's
going to do. And that says that he's
like God. And then finally,
um
the place is already holy. You know that
the place is already ready. You don't
need to make it holy. You don't need
anything. Um that that um it's already
ready to go. And then the final thing,
of course, is you know, Rit Meer's
depression marks where the ark's at.
that says that the temple is going to be
where or I say the temple the holy place
is going to be where it's been and it's
always been right now it's sitting under
the dome of the rock that's where it's
going to be and in its proper time it'll
be used for exactly what God has
intended it for. So folks that's my
position we're we're done. We're out of
time but I just want you to consider
that you don't you know as we go through
this people say it's impossible so it
can't happen with God all things are
possible. I believe that what we're
going to see is is
not going to have the temple the Dome of
the Rock blown away. It's going to
happen right where it's at. Folks, God
bless you. Uh it's good talking to you
again. Uh Colleen, look forward to
talking to you next Thursday, if not
before then.
>> Definitely. So, thank you, Steve.
>> And folks, God bless you until till
then. If you're not saved, get safe. If
you are safe, start living like it. Take
care and find yourself in the house of
the Lord this weekend. Bye-bye.
Thank you for viewing [music] this
episode of Last Days News presented by
Dr. Steve Taylor. Dr. Taylor invites you
to join him again [music] as he
continues to explore and define the
relationship between biblical prophecy
and the events we read about, hear of,
and see in the daily news. Last day's
news [music] is proudly sponsored by the
Alliance Legal and the Alliance
Bankruptcy Groups, collectively known as
[music] Alliance Law. For more
information about Alliance Law, you can
find them on the internet at
debtfreeva.com.
That is debtfreeva.com. [music]
Until next time, may the Lord bless and
keep you.